<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zoravur's Blog</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Zoravur's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:07:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zoravur.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Examples of Non-functional Requirements</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/functional-and-nonfunctional-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 12:07:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/functional-and-nonfunctional-requirements/</guid><description>&lt;p>The common refrain when determining functional and nonfunctional requirements is that
&amp;ldquo;functional requirements describe what the application does, and nonfunctional requirements
describe how it does it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some examples of nonfunctional requirements:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Performance
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Latency of various actions (page loads, content loading, server processing)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Availability
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Uptime requirements (which may vary from system to system)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scalability
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of users&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expected growth in users in 3 months, 6 months, a year, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Throughput&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Observability
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How easy it is to tell what is going on (or going wrong) with your application&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reliability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technology Stack&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security requirements
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Authentication&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Authorization&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintainability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Compliance
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>GDPR, COPPA, HIPAA, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Adopting Hugo</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/adopting-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 21:40:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/adopting-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am changing from raw html to the static site generator Hugo.
As I plan to put more writing on my blog, writing in markdown instead
of plain HTML will become more important. Stay tuned for overviews of
system design concepts (as I prepare to find more permanent employment),
as well as security and statistics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get excited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spock: A Spoken Programming Language</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/spock-a-spoken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/spock-a-spoken/</guid><description>&lt;p>In December 2023, I came up with the idea of a programming language you would be able to speak out loud, into your phone or computer, hands-free. I thought it was an interesting idea for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It would allow you to program on the go without a laptop, while still approaching threshold efficiency (130wpm output[^1]). Also, reducing the time from thought → action seemed like a powerful way to increase productivity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It would be an interesting experiment to see how voice programming would change software: Would being able to speak algorithms increase fluency with them? Would programming languages naturally become more terse and expressive, mirroring natural language? Would voice-written software libraries become spaghetti, or would the necessity of fitting the entire problem domain in your brain at once lead to more elegant solutions?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There are many voice assistants which run code on your behalf, but none that are Turing complete. A language that allows you to communicate any task that a computer can conceivably do would be the ultimate in power and flexibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really pursue the idea due to other projects, nor had I really done any work in programming languages since second year, so I was forced to give up on the idea. Nonetheless, I briefly reviewed my course notes and kept the idea on the back burner.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avoiding Enshittification</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/avoiding-enshittification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/avoiding-enshittification/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;/strong> The landscape of social media has become a battleground for attention, with platforms engaging in a relentless pursuit to retain users. This essay delves into the phenomenon of &amp;ldquo;enshittification&amp;rdquo;, a term coined to describe the progressive degradation of user experience on social media platforms. We explore the root causes of this issue and propose innovative solutions to counteract it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Problem of Enshittification:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enshittification in social media arises primarily from two interlinked factors. Firstly, the inherent design of these platforms aims to captivate users, offering an experience that is initially rewarding and potentially addictive. This user engagement is then monetized through advertising, subscriptions, or direct sales, often at the cost of user experience. Secondly, operating social media platforms is a financially intensive endeavor. The significant server costs and overheads render the idea of running such platforms as non-profits impractical.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/first/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/first/</guid><description>&lt;p>TODO:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Put up résumé&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create projects page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy Chris Lattner&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>