<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Zoravur's Blog</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Zoravur's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zoravur.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spock: A Spoken Programming Language</title><link>https://zoravur.github.io/spock-a-spoken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zoravur.github.io/spock-a-spoken/</guid><description>&lt;p>In December 2023, I came up with the idea of a programming language you would be able to speak out loud, into your phone or computer, hands-free. I thought it was an interesting idea for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It would allow you to program on the go without a laptop, while still approaching threshold efficiency (130wpm output[^1]). Also, reducing the time from thought → action seemed like a powerful way to increase productivity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It would be an interesting experiment to see how voice programming would change software: Would being able to speak algorithms increase fluency with them? Would programming languages naturally become more terse and expressive, mirroring natural language? Would voice-written software libraries become spaghetti, or would the necessity of fitting the entire problem domain in your brain at once lead to more elegant solutions?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There are many voice assistants which run code on your behalf, but none that are Turing complete. A language that allows you to communicate any task that a computer can conceivably do would be the ultimate in power and flexibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really pursue the idea due to other projects, nor had I really done any work in programming languages since second year, so I was forced to give up on the idea. Nonetheless, I briefly reviewed my course notes and kept the idea on the back burner.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>